Guide to the Abraham Unger Papers TAM.157
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Subject Files, 1930s-1970s
  - Legislative Documents: Miscellaneous, 1954, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Letter to Attorney-General Thomas Clark from Ferdinand C. Smith, John Williamson, Gerhardt Eisler, Charles A. Doyle re Deportation, Feb 23, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Logan-Walter Bill (Manuscript), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Marcantonio, Vito, 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Marine Workers League, early 1930s (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Marschall Plan: Anonymous Manuscripts Including "The Marshall Plan and American Foreign Policy", 1947-1948, undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Mattachine Society Inc. of New York, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - May Day, 1948-1952, undated (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - May Day, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - McCarran Act (Clippings), 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - McCarthyism (Clippings), 1953-1962, undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Medical Aid to Cuba Committee, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Memorandum In Support of the Challenge to the Seating of Mississippi Congressmen, Democratic Natioanl Convention, 1964, Sep 9, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Metropolitan Council on Housing, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Mihailovich, Draja, General - Yugoslavian Anti-Nazi Guerrilla Army Leader Tried by Tito (Clippings), 1946 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Military Law Related Documents, 1942, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party: Letter, Aug 11, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - The Mitchell Committee of Raleigh and Wake County (In Defense of African-American Attorney Samuel S. Mitchell), 1962 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Moorhead, William F.: Admission to New York State Bar, early 1940s (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Mundt-Nixon Bill (Analyses, Reports, Resolutions), 1948-1950, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Mundt-Nixon Bill (Clippings, Congressional Records, Fliers), 1948, undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Mundt-Nixon Bill: CPUSA Statements (Including Benjamin J. Davis' Testimony Before the House-committee on Un-American Activities), c. early 1950s (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - National Assembly for Democratic Rights, c. 1960s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - National Committee to Defend Dr. W.E.B. DuBois and Associates, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - National Committee to Repeal the McCarran Act: Petition to Pesident Kennedy, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - National Committee to Win Amnesty for Smith Act Victims, 1952-1954 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - National Conference for New Politics, 1966, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - National Conference To Win Amnesty for Smith Act Victims, 1952, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1965, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, Selective Service and Military Law Panel: Memmorandums, Minutes, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1941-1942, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - National Federation For Constitutional Liberties: Perjury Trial of George Hill, Secretary to Representative Hamilton Fisch, Jan 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - National Labor Relations Act, 1940, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National Non-Partisan Committee, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - National Unemployment League, 1937, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - New York City Elections (Labor Party, Etc.), 1947-1968 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - New York City Housing: Veterans, c. 1940s (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - New York City Sanitary Code (Digest), undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - New York City Public Housing, 1960-1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - New York City Public Housing (Clippings), 1952, 1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - New York County Lawyers' Association, 1953-1955 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - New York Draft and Military Law Panel, 1960-1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - New York State Commission Against Discrimation, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - New York State Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - New York University: Attempted Ransom of Computers by Radical Students (Clippings), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - New York University: Student Political Activism, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Nunan Bill, c. 1930s (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - The Ober Law (Requiring Registration of the Communist Party in Maryland), 1949 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Poll Tax, 1942-1945 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Post War Issues: International Politics, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Pressmann, Lee: "Analysis of the Taft-Hartley Bill as Reported by Conference Committee", Jun 2, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "Radical Lawyers", 1960s (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee, c. 1940 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Regler, Gustav: Formal International Brigade Member Now Willing To Testify on Behalf of U.S. State Department Against Communists, Apr 22-23, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Schlesinger, Hymen: Motion to Dismiss Complaint, c. 1950s (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Selective Service Law, 1967-1968, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Shibley Defense Committee, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Smith Act, 1953, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Sobell Committee, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Socialist Scholars Conference, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Soviet Espionage Trials, 1937-1949 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Spain: Francoism and Political Prisoners in the 1960s (Clippings), 1961, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (To Help Qualified Colored Voters to Vote), 1968 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Stuyvesant Town, New York, NY, 1947-1950, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Taylor, [Glenn?]: Speeches, c. 1950 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Teachers' Union, New York City, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Theatre Guild, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Titoism (Clippings), 1950-1958 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - "Titoism" (Anonymous Manuscript), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Trade Union Committee to Defend Louis Weinstock, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Travel Rights, 1955, undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - The United Nations Charter: The Rule of Law and the Conduct of the United States Government in Vietnam and the Dominican Republic, Jul 23, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - United Nations Convenant on Human Nations, 1948-1950, undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Vietnam (Clippings), 1966-1970 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Vietnam (Printed Ephemera), 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Vigilantes Republica (Designated Abraham Unger as "Enemy of the United States"), 1950s (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Walter Omnibus Bill, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Washington Heights Tenants Association, early 1970s (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Witt, Nathan; Lee Pressman; John Abt: Statements Before the House Committee of Un-American Activities, 1948, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Wood Bill: Military Subversion, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - World Conference of Lawyers for Vietnam (Grenoble, France, July 6-10, 1968) (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - World Peace Movements, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Youth Court Act, New York State, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Youth to Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities, 1960-1963, undated (Box 10, Folder 63)
- Series VI: 2016 Accretion
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains clippings, writings, and correspondence related to Abraham Unger's work in support of individuals involved in the movement for Puerto Rican independence. These materials primarily relate the cases of Puerto Rican Independence Movement members Oscar Collazo and Juan Bernardo Lebron. Unger served as Callazo’s defense attorney after Callazo and an associate attempted to assassinate President Harry Truman in 1950. Unger also served as council for Lebron who was brought on conspiracy charges for his connection with an attack on the US House of Representatives in 1954. Lebron was charged along with several other defendants, but was the only defendant represented by Unger. Materials related to Lebron's case primarily consist of legal briefs, Unger's notes, and correspondence between 1954 and 1955. The collection also contains general clippings and articles related to Puerto Rico and the independence movement and its leader Pedro Abizu Campos. Other materials in this donation include incoming letters to Unger (1948-1957), planning materials from the 17th Annual Communist Party National Convention, and articles related to communism and human rights.
  - Research Materials on Puerto Rico and Puerto RIcan Political Prisoners, 1950-1966 (Box 11, Box 14)
  - General Articles and Bulletins on Communism and Socialism, 1948-1980 (Box 11, Box 13)
  - Oscar Collazo Clemency Petition, 1948-1972 (Box 11, Box 12)
  - Juan Lebron Defense in United States vs. Lebron, 1953-1959 (Box 12)
  - Pedro Abizu Campos and the Puerto Rican Independence Movement, 1952-1976 (Box 12)
  - Communist Party 17th National Convention, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Letters to Abraham Unger, 1948-1957 (Box 13)
  - Articles on World Peace through Law, 1956-1964 (Box 13, Box 14)